Bastien Mussard

Software Engineer

French national - 31 years old Resume produced on June 28, 2019 (Bold elements clickable)

Scientist by training, looking today for a job

effectively always been at the core of my work.Accustomed to work on cross-functional projects.

leaning more toward programming, which has

- Good dialogue with people of broad backgrounds.
- Team work to launch new features, from creation to production phase.
- Communication on results and innovations, including through the design of helpful data visualization aids.

Creativity

Global thinking

Curiosity

Adaptability

Tenacity

Team-player



EXPERIENCES

Postdoctorate

2017 - 2019

University of Colorado, Boulder, USA Contact: Sandeep Sharma

Lead a team of 4 PhD candidates. Handling of large operation and data flows. Design and creation of scalable algorithms. Set up best practices and continuous integration.

Invited researcher

July 2016

University of Cornell, Ithaca, USA Contact: Cyrus Umrigar

Unified implementations to boost performance. Wrote user/developer docs for complex codes.

Research Engineer

2014 - 2017

Sorbonne University, Paris Contact: Julien Toulouse

Tasked with production and maintenance of codes. Optimized core routines in widely used algorithms. Developed user-friendly libraries for key tasks. Design and creation of naturally interfacing codes.

➤ bastien.mussard@gmail.com

mussard.github.io

in in/bastien-mussard



SKILLS

Linux, Bash, Unix				
Python				
C, C++			0	0
Git, SVN				0
Continuous Integration		0	0	0
Machine Learning		0	0	0

Bilingual <u>French</u> (native) and <u>English</u> (daily practical use both personnally and professionally; lived 3 years in the United States).



PRODUCTIONS

15 scientific publications and significant contributions to major scientific codes:

- **Molpro**: a comprehensive system of commercial programs for advanced calculations.
 - In charge of management and support.

 Improved the performance of parts of the code.
- **Dice**: a modern code that takes advantage of the latest advances in the domain, written in C.

 Implementation of most new features.
- **PySCF**: a theoretical chemistry program easy to use, coded in Python and C.
 - Handling of interfaces between languages.
- **CHAMP**: a code using stochastic processes.

 Implementation of fast and efficient calculations.



EDUCATION AND DEGREES

PhD 2010 - 2013

Université de Lorraine, Nancy

MSc 2007 - 2010

École Normale Supérieure, Paris



INTERESTS

Teaching, Outreach, Swimming, Reading, Hiking